<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><measure><measureDetails><uuid>8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612a40d0e</uuid><title>Home Management Plan of Care (HMPC) Document Given to Patient/Caregiver</title><shortTitle>CAC-3</shortTitle><emeasureid>26</emeasureid><guid>e1cb05e0-97d5-40fc-b456-15c5dbf44309</guid><version>2</version><status>In Progress</status><nqfid extension="0338" root="2.16.840.1.113883.3.560.1"/><period uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d1f"><startDate uuid="5f9059e0-e30f-4591-9c0b-0a9ecbc1c7d2">00000101</startDate><stopDate uuid="41d06178-ac7c-417f-bbe2-ca3492bdf5a3">00001231</stopDate></period><steward id="1.3.6.1.4.1.33895">Joint Commission</steward><developers><developer id="1.3.6.1.4.1.33895">Joint Commission</developer></developers><endorsement id="2.16.840.1.113883.3.560">National Quality Forum</endorsement><description>An assessment that there is documentation in the medical record that a Home Management Plan of Care (HMPC) document was given to the pediatric asthma patient/caregiver.</description><copyright>LOINC(R) is a registered trademark of the Regenstrief Institute.&#xD;
&#xD;
This material contains SNOMED Clinical Terms (R) (SNOMED CT(c)) copyright 2004-2010 International Health Terminology Standards Development Organization. All rights reserved.</copyright><disclaimer>None</disclaimer><scoring id="PROPOR">Proportion</scoring><types><type id="PROCESS">Process</type></types><stratification>None</stratification><riskAdjustment>None</riskAdjustment><aggregation>None</aggregation><rationale>Asthma is the most common chronic disease in children and a major cause of morbidity and health care costs nationally (Adams, et al., 2001). For children, asthma is one of the most frequent reasons for admission to hospitals (McCormick, et al., 1999). Silber, et al., (2003) noted that there are approximately 200,000 admissions for childhood asthma in the United States annually, representing more than $3 billion dollars in expenditures. Under-treatment and/or inappropriate treatment of asthma are recognized as major contributors to asthma morbidity and mortality. Guidelines developed by the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program (NAEPP) of the National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute (NHLBI), as well as by the American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) for the diagnosis and management of asthma in children, recommend establishing a plan for maintaining control of asthma and for establishing plans for managing exacerbations. Both aspects of care would include instructions related to pharmacotherapy and assessment of lung function. &#xD;
&#xD;
According to the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), an Evidence-based Practice Center (EPC) and Aronson, Lefevere, Piper, et al. (2001) reported that increasing use of controller medications improves outcomes. Children with asthma who are seen by specialists or receive follow-up appointments are more likely to use appropriate long-term control medications (ACQA, 2004; Finklestein, Lozano, Farber, et al., 2002). &#xD;
&#xD;
Organization of care towards patient self-management and patient/caregiver routine education on appropriate use of asthma medications, identification of symptoms of exacerbation, avoidance of environmental triggers cannot be overemphasized (AHRQ, 2005). For children, it is particularly important to involve both the patient and the caregiver in this educational component of asthma care as participation in the plan of care by both will provide the greatest opportunity to promote compliance with the treatment plan, control of asthma, and treatment of exacerbations in a safe and timely manner.</rationale><recommendations>Under-treatment and/or inappropriate treatment of asthma are recognized as major contributors to asthma morbidity and mortality. National guidelines for the diagnosis and management of asthma in children, recommend establishing a plan for maintaining control of asthma and for establishing plans for managing exacerbation.</recommendations><improvementNotations>An increase in the rate.</improvementNotations><references><reference>Adams RJ, Fuhlbrigge A, Finkelstein JA, Lozano P, Livingston JM, Weiss KB, and Weiss ST (2001). Use of Inhaled Anti-inflammatory Medication in Children with Asthma in Managed Care Settings. Archives of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, 155, 501-507.</reference><reference>Aronson N, Lefevere F, Piper M, et al. (September 2001). Management of chronic asthma. Evidence Report/Technology Assessment Number 44. (Prepared by Blue Cross and Blue Shield Association Technology Evaluation Center under Contract No. 290-97-0015.) AHRQ Pub. No. 01-E044. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality.</reference><reference>Asthma Care Quality Assessment Study (ACQA) (1998-2003). Asthma care quality in varying managed care Medicaid plans. Harvard Medical School. Grant No. U01-HS09935.</reference><reference>Asthma Management Model System, http://www.nhlbi.nih.gov</reference><reference>Bhogal S, Zemek R, Ducharme FM, Written action plans for asthma in children.  Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2006 Jul 19;3:CD005306.</reference><reference>Clinical Practice Guidelines of the American Academy of Pediatrics: A Compendium of Evidence-Based Research for Pediatric Practice. American Academy of Pediatrics (1999).</reference><reference>Crain EF, Weiss KB and Fagan MJ (1995). Pediatric Asthma Care in U.S. Emergency Departments. Archives of Pediatric and Adolescent Medicine. 149, 893-901.</reference><reference>Ducharme FM, Bhogal SK. The role of written action plans in childhood asthma.  Curr Opin Allergy Clin Immunol. 2008 Apr;8(2):177-88.</reference><reference>Finkelstein JA, Lozano P, Farber HJ, et al. (2002). Underuse of controller medications among Medicaid-insured children with asthma. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med 156(6):562-7.</reference><reference>McCormick MC, Kass B, Elixhauser A, Thompson J and Simpson L (2000). Annual Report on Access to and Utilization of Health Care for Children and Youth in the United States ? 1999. Pediatrics, 105:1, 219-230.</reference><reference>National Asthma Education and Prevention Program, http://www.nhlbi.nih.gov</reference><reference>National Institutes of Health, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute. National Asthma Education and Prevention Program. Expert panel report 3: guidelines for the diagnosis and management of asthma, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda (2007) NIH publication no. 07-4051.</reference><reference>Schramm CM, Carroll CL. Advances in treating acute asthma exacerbations in children.  Curr Opin Pediatr. 2009 Jun;21(3):326-32.</reference><reference>Silber JH, Rosenbaum PR, Even-Shoshan O, Shabbout M, Zhang X, Bradlow ET, and Marsh RR (2003). Length of Stay, Conditional Length of Stay, and Prolonged Stay in Pediatric Asthma. Health Services Research, 38: 3, 867-886.</reference><reference>Stanton MW, Dougherty D, Rutherford MK. (2005). Chronic care for low-income children with asthma: strategies for improvement. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality. Research in Action Issue 18. AHRQ Pub. No. 05-0073.</reference></references><definitions>None</definitions><guidance>The home management plan of care document should be a separate and patient-specific written instruction. The document must be present in the form of an explicit and separate document specific to the patient rather than components or segments of the plan spread across discharge instruction sheets, discharge orders, education sheets, or other instruction sheets.&#xD;
&#xD;
The home management plan of care is represented in the eMeasure logic by a LOINC code for an asthma action plan document. This form, or equivalent, contains most of the components required for the home management plan of care, including information on:&#xD;
?	Methods and timing of rescue actions: the home management plan of care addresses what to do if asthma symptoms worsen after discharge, including all of the following: 1) When to take action, i.e., assessment of severity (e.g., peak flow meter reading, signs and symptoms to watch for); 2) What specific steps to take, i.e., initial treatment instructions (e.g., inhaled relievers up to three treatments of 2-4 puffs by MDI at 20-minute intervals or single nebulizer treatment); 3) Contact information to be used, when an asthma attack occurs or is about to occur.&#xD;
?	Appropriate use of long-term asthma medications (controllers), including the medication name, dose, frequency, and method of administration.&#xD;
?	Appropriate use of rescue, quick-relief, or short acting medications of choice to quickly relieve asthma exacerbations (relievers), including the medication name, dose, frequency, and method of administration.&#xD;
?	Environmental control and control of other triggers: information on avoidance or mitigation of environmental and other triggers.&#xD;
&#xD;
In addition to the information outlined in the asthma action plan form (or equivalent document), the home management plan of care is required to include information regarding arrangements for referral or follow-up care with a healthcare provider, namely:&#xD;
?	If an appointment for referral or follow-up care with a healthcare provider has been made, the home management plan of care is required to include the provider/clinic/office name, as well as the date and time of the appointment.&#xD;
?	If an appointment for referral of follow-up care with a healthcare provider has NOT been made, the home management plan of care is required to include information for the patient/caregiver to be able to make arrangements for follow-up care, i.e., provider/clinic/office name, telephone number and time frame for appointment for follow-up care (e.g., 7-10 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
The home management plan of care can only be considered to comply with the criteria outlined in the measure logic if it meets the requirements outlined above and is appropriately filled-out with information specific to the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
Patient refusal includes refusal by a caregiver. The caregiver is defined as the patient?s family or any other person (e.g., home health, VNA provider, prison official or other law enforcement personnel) who will be responsible for care of the patient after discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
The ?Discharge To Home Or Police Custody? value set also intends to capture the following discharge disposition values:&#xD;
? Assisted Living Facilities&#xD;
? Court/Law Enforcement ? includes detention facilities, jails, and prison&#xD;
? Home ? includes board and care, foster or residential care, group or personal care homes, and homeless shelters&#xD;
? Home with Home Health Services&#xD;
? Outpatient Services including outpatient procedures at another hospital, Outpatient Chemical Dependency Programs and Partial Hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
The unit of measurement for this measure is an inpatient episode of care. Each distinct hospitalization should be reported, regardless of whether the same patient is admitted for inpatient care more than once during the measurement period. In addition, the eMeasure logic intends to represent events within or surrounding a single occurrence of an inpatient hospitalization.</guidance><transmissionFormat>None</transmissionFormat><initialPatientPopDescription>Pediatric asthma inpatients with an age of 2 through 17 years, and length of stay less than or equal to 120 days.</initialPatientPopDescription><denominatorDescription>Pediatric asthma inpatients with an age of 2 through 17 years, length of stay less than or equal to 120 days, and discharged to home or police custody.</denominatorDescription><denominatorExclusionsDescription>None</denominatorExclusionsDescription><numeratorDescription>Pediatric asthma inpatients with documentation that they or their caregivers were given a written Home Management Plan of Care (HMPC) document that addresses all of the following: &#xD;
1. Arrangements for follow-up care &#xD;
2. Environmental control and control of other triggers&#xD;
3. Method and timing of rescue actions&#xD;
4. Use of controllers &#xD;
5. Use of relievers</numeratorDescription><numeratorExclusionsDescription>Not applicable</numeratorExclusionsDescription><denominatorExceptionsDescription>None</denominatorExceptionsDescription><measurePopulationDescription>Not applicable</measurePopulationDescription><measureObservationsDescription>Not applicable</measureObservationsDescription><supplementalData>For every patient evaluated by this measure also identify payer, race, ethnicity and sex.</supplementalData><qualityMeasureSet uuid="da0a471c-ff83-48b7-8654-560c897c4c73">eMeasure Children?s Asthma Care (eCAC)</qualityMeasureSet>
<finalizedDate value="201402131531-0600"/>
</measureDetails><supplementalDataElements><elementRef id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d0f" name="ONC Administrative Sex"/><elementRef id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d10" name="Race"/><elementRef id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d11" name="Ethnicity"/><elementRef id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d12" name="Payer"/></supplementalDataElements><measureGrouping><group sequence="1"><clause displayName="Initial Patient Population 1" type="initialPatientPopulation" uuid="D34455EF-E08F-41A8-9AC5-2580DE0965F2"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><relationalOp displayName="Starts During" type="SDU"><elementRef displayName="Asthma : Diagnosis, Active" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d21" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="ordinality" qdmUUID="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d22"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of Inpatient Encounter : Encounter, Performed" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><relationalOp displayName="&gt;= 2 years Starts Before Start Of" operatorType="Greater Than or Equal To" quantity="2" type="SBS" unit="years"><elementRef displayName="birth date : Patient Characteristic Birthdate" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b30d2f" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of Inpatient Encounter : Encounter, Performed" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 17 years Starts Before Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="17" type="SBS" unit="years"><elementRef displayName="birth date : Patient Characteristic Birthdate" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b30d2f" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of Inpatient Encounter : Encounter, Performed" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of Inpatient Encounter : Encounter, Performed" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="120" mode="Less Than or Equal To" name="length of stay" unit="days"/></elementRef><relationalOp displayName="During" type="DURING"><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of Inpatient Encounter : Encounter, Performed" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Check if Present" name="discharge datetime"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Measurement Period : Timing Element" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d1f" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></logicalOp></clause><clause displayName="Denominator 1" type="denominator" uuid="7EF86DE1-2004-4115-B48E-CA154CDAF4F7"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of Inpatient Encounter : Encounter, Performed" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="discharge status" qdmUUID="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d17"/></elementRef></logicalOp></clause><clause displayName="Numerator 1" type="numerator" uuid="4C2516F9-21A7-4A65-AE29-CCA8857FD61D"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><relationalOp displayName="During" type="DURING"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Asthma Management Plan : Communication: From Provider to Patient" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-521888af0db7" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Asthma Management Plan : Communication: From Provider to Patient" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-521888af0db7" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="negation rationale" qdmUUID="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b30d2c"/></elementRef></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of Inpatient Encounter : Encounter, Performed" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></logicalOp></clause></group></measureGrouping><elementLookUp><qdm codeSystemName="National Library of Medicine" datatype="Patient Characteristic Sex" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d0f" name="ONC Administrative Sex" oid="2.16.840.1.113762.1.4.1" suppDataElement="true" taxonomy="Administrative Sex" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d0f" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="CDC NCHS" datatype="Patient Characteristic Race" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d10" name="Race" oid="2.16.840.1.114222.4.11.836" suppDataElement="true" taxonomy="CDC" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d10" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="CDC NCHS" datatype="Patient Characteristic Ethnicity" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d11" name="Ethnicity" oid="2.16.840.1.114222.4.11.837" suppDataElement="true" taxonomy="CDC" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d11" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="PHDSC" datatype="Patient Characteristic Payer" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d12" name="Payer" oid="2.16.840.1.114222.4.11.3591" suppDataElement="true" taxonomy="Source of Payment Typology" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b10d12" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Joint Commission" datatype="attribute" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d17" name="Discharge To Home Or Police Custody" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.117.1.7.1.82" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d17" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="National Quality Forum" datatype="Timing Element" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d1f" name="Measurement Period" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.67.1.101.1.53" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="NQF" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d1f" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Joint Commission" datatype="Diagnosis, Active" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d21" name="Asthma" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.117.1.7.1.271" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d21" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Joint Commission" datatype="attribute" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d22" name="Principal Diagnosis" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.117.2.7.1.14" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b20d22" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Joint Commission" datatype="attribute" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b30d2c" name="Patient Refusal" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.117.1.7.1.93" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b30d2c" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="National Quality Forum" datatype="Patient Characteristic Birthdate" id="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b30d2f" name="birth date" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.560.100.4" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="LOINC" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd612b30d2f" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Joint Commission" datatype="Encounter, Performed" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" instance="Occurrence A" name="Inpatient Encounter" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.117.1.7.1.23" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-415f5aff3615" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Joint Commission" datatype="Communication: From Provider to Patient" id="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-521888af0db7" name="Asthma Management Plan" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.117.1.7.1.131" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="LOINC" uuid="8a4d92b2-3a00-2a25-013a-521888af0db7" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Joint Commission" datatype="Encounter, Performed" id="668a0316-90f7-4e08-bfac-429bebbc4191" name="Inpatient Encounter" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.117.1.7.1.23" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="668a0316-90f7-4e08-bfac-429bebbc4191" version="1"/></elementLookUp><strata displayName="Stratification"><clause displayName="Stratum 1" type="stratum" uuid="8a4d92b2-37bf-6f1b-0137-ccd61cfd0d88"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"/></clause></strata></measure>
