<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><measure><measureDetails><uuid>40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc6b5642</uuid><title>Preventive Care and Screening:  Screening for High Blood Pressure and Follow-Up Documented</title><shortTitle>CMS22</shortTitle><emeasureid>22</emeasureid><finalizedDate>05/17/2013 01:13 PM</finalizedDate><guid>9a033a94-3d9b-11e1-8634-00237d5bf174</guid><version>2</version><status>In Progress</status><nqfid extension="Not Applicable" root="2.16.840.1.113883.3.560.1"/><period uuid="61e88419-9d84-4753-a25a-e869d30850ca"><startDate uuid="fa6e22f1-5982-4da9-99e0-75a33d72edac">00000101</startDate><stopDate uuid="6cfc4570-157e-4c00-a7f2-766805be5900">00001231</stopDate></period><steward id="7495edf3-5338-4e5f-947a-2101b683eef4">Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services</steward><developers><developer id="f9e75a20-68ed-4a29-9b11-10feaea3370c">Quality Insights of Pennsylvania</developer></developers><description>Percentage of patients aged 18 years and older seen during the reporting period who were screened for high blood pressure AND a recommended follow-up plan is documented based on the current blood pressure (BP) reading as indicated</description><copyright>Limited proprietary coding is contained in the measure specifications for convenience. Users of the proprietary code sets should obtain all necessary licenses from the owners of these code sets. Quality Insights of Pennsylvania disclaims all liability for use or accuracy of any Current Procedural Terminology (CPT [R]) or other coding contained in the specifications.&#13;
&#13;
CPT (R) contained in the Measure specifications is copyright 2007-2011 American Medical Association. &#13;
&#13;
LOINC (R) copyright 2004-2011 Regenstrief Institute, Inc. This material contains SNOMED Clinical Terms (R) (SNOMED CT [R]) copyright 2004-2011 International Health Terminology Standards Development Organization. All Rights Reserved.&#13;
&#13;
Due to technical limitations, registered trademarks are indicated by (R) or [R] and unregistered trademarks are indicated by (TM) or [TM].</copyright><disclaimer>These performance measures are not clinical guidelines and do not establish a standard of medical care, and have not been tested for all potential applications.&#13;
&#13;
THE MEASURES AND SPECIFICATIONS ARE PROVIDED ?AS IS? WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND.</disclaimer><scoring id="PROPOR">Proportion</scoring><types><type id="PROCESS">Process</type></types><stratification>None</stratification><riskAdjustment>None</riskAdjustment><aggregation>None</aggregation><rationale>Hypertension is a prevalent condition that affects approximately 66.9 million people in the United States. It is estimated that about 20-40% of the adult population has hypertension; the majority of people over age 65 have a hypertension diagnosis (Appleton SL, et. al., 2012 and Luehr D, et. al., 2012). Winter (2013) noted that 1 in 3 American adults have hypertension and the lifetime risk of developing hypertension is 90% (Winter KH, et. al., 2013). The African American population or non-Hispanic Blacks, the elderly, diabetics and those with chronic kidney disease are at increased risk of stroke, myocardial infarction and renal disease. Non-Hispanic Blacks have the highest prevalence at 38.6% (Winter KH, et. al., 2013). Hypertension is a major risk factor for ischemic heart disease, left ventricular hypertrophy, renal failure, stroke and dementia (Luehr D, et. al., 2012). &#13;
&#13;
&#13;
Hypertension is the most common reason for adult office visits other than pregnancy. Garrison (2013) stated that in 2007, 42 million ambulatory visits were attributed to hypertension (Garrison GM and Oberhelman S, 2013). It also has the highest utilization of prescription drugs. Numerous resources and treatment options are available, yet only about 40-50% of the hypertensive patients have their blood pressure under control (&lt;140/90) (Appleton SL, et. al., 2012, Luehr D, et. al., 2012). In addition to medication non-compliance, poor outcomes are also attributed to poor adherence to lifestyle changes such as a low-sodium diet, weight loss, increased exercise and limiting alcohol intake.  Many adults find it difficult to continue medications and lifestyle changes when they are asymptomatic.  Symptoms of elevated blood pressure usually do not occur until secondary problems arise such as with vascular diseases (myocardial infarction, stroke, heart failure and renal insufficiency) (Luehr D, et. al., 2012).&#13;
&#13;
Appropriate follow-up after blood pressure measurement is a pivotal component in preventing the progression of hypertension and the development of heart disease. Detection of marginally or fully elevated blood pressure by a specialty clinician warrants referral to a provider familiar with the management of hypertension and prehypertension.  The 2010 ACCF/AHA Guideline for the Assessment of Cardiovascular Risk in Asymptomatic Adults continues to support using a global risk score such as the Framingham Risk Score, to assess risk of coronary heart disease (CHD) in all asymptomatic adults (Greenland P, et. al., 2010).  Lifestyle modifications have demonstrated effectiveness in lowering blood pressure (JNC 7, 2003).  The synergistic effect of several lifestyle modifications results in greater benefits than a single modification alone. Baseline diagnostic/laboratory testing establishes if a co-existing underlying condition is the etiology of hypertension and evaluates if end organ damage from hypertension has already occurred. Landmark trials such as ALLHAT have repeatedly proven the efficacy of pharmacologic therapy to control blood pressure and reduce the complications of hypertension.  Follow-up intervals based on blood pressure control have been established by the JNC 7 and the USPSTF.</rationale><recommendations>The U.S. Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) recommends screening for high blood pressure in adults age 18 years and older. This is a grade A recommendation.</recommendations><improvementNotations>Higher score indicates better quality.</improvementNotations><references><reference>U.S. Preventive Services Task Force (USPSTF) (2007). Screening for high blood pressure: U.S. Preventive Services Task Force reaffirmation recommendation statement. Annals of Internal Medicine; 147(11):783-6</reference><reference>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, National Institutes of Health, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute &amp; National High Blood Pressure Education Program (2003). The Seventh Report of the Joint National Committee on the Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure (JNC-7). NIH Publication No. 03-5233</reference><reference>Garrison GM &amp; Oberhelman S (2013). Screening for hypertension annually compared with current practice. Annals of Family Medicine, 11 (2), 116-121.</reference><reference>Luehr D, Woolley T, Burke R, Dohmen F, Hayes R, Johnson M, Kerandi H, Margolis K, Marshall M, O'Connor P, Pereira C, Reddy G, Schlichte A &amp; Schoenleber M (2012). Hypertension diagnosis and treatment; Institute for Clinical Systems Improvement health care guideline. Updated November, 2012.</reference><reference>Appleton SL, Neo C, Hill C L, Douglas K A &amp; Adams R J (2012). Untreated hypertension: prevalence and patient factors and beliefs associated with under-treatment in a population sample. Journal of Human Hypertension, advance online publication December 13, 2012.</reference><reference>Winter K H, Tuttle L A &amp; Viera A J (2013). Hypertension. Prim Care Clin Office Pract, 40, 179-194.</reference></references><definitions>Blood Pressure (BP) Classification: &#13;
BP is defined by four (4) BP reading classifications: Normal, Pre-Hypertensive, First Hypertensive, and Second Hypertensive Readings&#13;
&#13;
Recommended BP Follow-Up: &#13;
The current Report of the Joint National Committee on the Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure (JNC) recommends BP screening intervals, lifestyle modifications and interventions based on the current BP reading as listed in the ?Recommended Blood Pressure Follow-Up Interventions? listed below&#13;
&#13;
Recommended Lifestyle Modifications: &#13;
The current JNC report outlines lifestyle modifications which must include one or more of the following as indicated:&#13;
?  Weight Reduction&#13;
?  DASH Eating Plan &#13;
?  Dietary Sodium Restriction&#13;
?  Increased Physical Activity&#13;
?  Moderation in alcohol (ETOH) Consumption&#13;
&#13;
Second Hypertensive Reading: &#13;
Requires a BP reading of Systolic BP &gt;= 140 mmHg OR Diastolic BP &gt;= 90 mmHg during the current encounter AND a most recent BP reading within the last 12 months Systolic BP &gt;= 140 mmHg OR Diastolic BP &gt;= 90 mmHg&#13;
&#13;
Second Hypertensive Reading BP Interventions:  &#13;
The current JNC report outlines BP follow-up interventions for a second hypertensive BP reading and must include one or more of the following as indicated:&#13;
?  Anti-Hypertensive Pharmacologic Therapy &#13;
?  Laboratory Tests &#13;
?  Electrocardiogram (ECG)&#13;
&#13;
Recommended Blood Pressure Follow-Up Interventions:&#13;
?  Normal BP: No follow-up required for Systolic BP &lt; 120 mmHg AND Diastolic BP &lt;80 mmHg&#13;
?  Pre-Hypertensive BP: Follow-up with rescreen every year with systolic BP of 120-139 mmHg OR diastolic BP of 80-89 mmHg AND recommend lifestyle modifications OR referral to Alternative/Primary Care Provider&#13;
?  First Hypertensive BP Reading: Patients with one elevated reading of systolic BP &gt;= 140 mmHg OR diastolic BP &gt;= 90 mmHg: Follow-up with rescreen &gt; 1 day and &lt; 4 weeks AND  recommend lifestyle modifications OR referral to Alternative/Primary Care Provider  &#13;
?  Second Hypertensive BP Reading: Patients with second elevated reading of  systolic BP &gt;=140 mmHg OR diastolic BP &gt;= 90 mmHg:  Follow-up with Recommended lifestyle recommendations  AND one or more of the Second Hypertensive Reading Interventions OR referral to Alternative/Primary Care Provider</definitions><guidance>Both the systolic and diastolic blood pressure measurements are required for inclusion. If there are multiple blood pressures on the same date of service, use the lowest systolic and lowest diastolic blood pressure on that date as the representative blood pressure.&#13;
&#13;
Eligible professionals who report the measure must perform the blood pressure screening at the time of a qualifying visit by an eligible professional and may not obtain measurements from external sources. &#13;
&#13;
The documented follow up plan must be related to the current BP reading as indicated, example: ?Patient referred to primary care provider for BP management.?</guidance><transmissionFormat>TBD</transmissionFormat><initialPatientPopDescription>Percentage of patients aged 18 years and older before the start of the measurement period</initialPatientPopDescription><denominatorDescription>Equals Initial Patient Population</denominatorDescription><denominatorExclusionsDescription>Patient has an active diagnosis of hypertension</denominatorExclusionsDescription><numeratorDescription>Patients who were screened for high blood pressure AND have a recommended follow-up plan documented, as indicated if the blood pressure is pre-hypertensive or hypertensive</numeratorDescription><numeratorExclusionsDescription>Not Applicable.</numeratorExclusionsDescription><denominatorExceptionsDescription>Patient Reason(s): &#13;
Patient refuses to participate&#13;
&#13;
OR&#13;
&#13;
Medical Reason(s):&#13;
Patient is in an urgent or emergent medical situation where time is of the essence and to delay treatment would jeopardize the patient?s health status.  This may include but is not limited to severely elevated BP when immediate medical treatment is indicated.</denominatorExceptionsDescription><measurePopulationDescription>Not Applicable.</measurePopulationDescription><measureObservationsDescription>Not Applicable.</measureObservationsDescription><supplementalData>For every patient evaluated by this measure also identify payer, race, ethnicity and sex.</supplementalData><qualityMeasureSet uuid="95d7e296-8465-4f01-a9f5-3d1d5ffa7db3">Preventive Care and Screening</qualityMeasureSet></measureDetails><supplementalDataElements><elementRef id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567d" name="ONC Administrative Sex"/><elementRef id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567e" name="Race"/><elementRef id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567f" name="Ethnicity"/><elementRef id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc905680" name="Payer"/></supplementalDataElements><measureGrouping><group sequence="1"><clause displayName="Initial Patient Population 1" type="initialPatientPopulation" uuid="84C027B2-4A2A-4B67-8604-6434DA1EFA26"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><relationalOp displayName="&gt;= 18 years Starts Before Start Of" operatorType="Greater Than or Equal To" quantity="18" type="SBS" unit="years"><elementRef displayName="birth date : Patient Characteristic Birthdate" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc905681" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Measurement Period : Timing Element" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564c" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><functionalOp displayName="MOST RECENT" type="MOST RECENT" uuid="a1df3246-0ec0-42d0-b574-d7dcd4908049"><relationalOp displayName="During" type="DURING"><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Measurement Period : Timing Element" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564c" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></functionalOp></logicalOp></clause><clause displayName="Denominator 1" type="denominator" uuid="04FF6664-3C15-49AF-B3BA-7E66A759EF3E"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"/></clause><clause displayName="Denominator Exclusions 1" type="denominatorExclusions" uuid="B8E6E6B6-D82C-4B57-A85A-593971707EE4"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><relationalOp displayName="Starts Before Start Of" type="SBS"><elementRef displayName="Diagnosis of hypertension grouped : Diagnosis, Active" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564d" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></logicalOp></clause><clause displayName="Denominator Exceptions 1" type="denominatorExceptions" uuid="4EC864F1-84EB-45D8-B763-AA16E0BF7153"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><relationalOp displayName="Starts During" type="SDU"><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8e5656" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="negation rationale" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567c"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><relationalOp displayName="Starts During" type="SDU"><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8e5656" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="negation rationale" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5666"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><relationalOp displayName="Starts During" type="SDU"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8e5657" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="negation rationale" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567c"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><relationalOp displayName="Starts During" type="SDU"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8e5657" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="negation rationale" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5666"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp></clause><clause displayName="Numerator 1" type="numerator" uuid="DCB0122B-D2CA-4BB6-9A97-6DA1FC0FD2D5"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><relationalOp displayName="During" type="DURING"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="120" mode="Less Than" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="80" mode="Less Than" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><relationalOp displayName="During" type="DURING"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="120" mode="Greater Than or Equal To" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="80" mode="Greater Than or Equal To" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef></logicalOp><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="140" mode="Less Than" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="90" mode="Less Than" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef></logicalOp></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><elementRef displayName="Referral to Alternative Provider / Primary Care Provider : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566c" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="reason" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5648"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Lifestyle Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566e" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Weight Reduction Recommended : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566f" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Dietary Recommendations : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5670" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Physical Activity Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5671" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Moderation of ETOH Consumption Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5672" type="qdm"/></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><elementRef displayName="Followup within one year : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566d" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="reason" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5648"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><functionalOp displayName="MOST RECENT &lt; 1 years" operatorType="Less Than" quantity="1" type="MOST RECENT" unit="years" uuid="3e18f3fc-366d-4099-bf3d-8b25ad124c55"><relationalOp displayName="Starts Before Start Of" type="SBS"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="140" mode="Less Than" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="90" mode="Less Than" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></functionalOp><relationalOp displayName="&lt; 1 years Starts Before Start Of" operatorType="Less Than" quantity="1" type="SBS" unit="years"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><functionalOp displayName="NOT" type="NOT" uuid="febacaa5-15ba-491c-bd61-9bf85ad6a355"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" type="qdm"/></functionalOp><functionalOp displayName="NOT" type="NOT" uuid="6004bcf2-9b8c-4b1b-bb27-31b25643f72b"><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" type="qdm"/></functionalOp></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></logicalOp><relationalOp displayName="During" type="DURING"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="140" mode="Greater Than or Equal To" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="90" mode="Greater Than or Equal To" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><elementRef displayName="Referral to Alternative Provider / Primary Care Provider : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566c" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="reason" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5648"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Lifestyle Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566e" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Weight Reduction Recommended : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566f" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Dietary Recommendations : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5670" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Physical Activity Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5671" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Moderation of ETOH Consumption Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5672" type="qdm"/></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><elementRef displayName="Followup within 4 weeks : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5677" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="reason" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5648"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><functionalOp displayName="MOST RECENT &lt; 1 years" operatorType="Less Than" quantity="1" type="MOST RECENT" unit="years" uuid="03d2626a-a671-464c-a445-e6eb67870329"><relationalOp displayName="Starts Before Start Of" type="SBS"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="140" mode="Greater Than or Equal To" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="90" mode="Greater Than or Equal To" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></functionalOp><relationalOp displayName="During" type="DURING"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Systolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="140" mode="Greater Than or Equal To" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Diastolic Blood Pressure : Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" type="qdm"><attribute comparisonValue="90" mode="Greater Than or Equal To" name="result" unit="mmHg"/></elementRef></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><elementRef displayName="Referral to Alternative Provider / Primary Care Provider : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566c" type="qdm"><attribute mode="Value Set" name="reason" qdmUUID="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5648"/></elementRef><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Lifestyle Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566e" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Weight Reduction Recommended : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566f" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Dietary Recommendations : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5670" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Physical Activity Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5671" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Moderation of ETOH Consumption Recommendation : Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5672" type="qdm"/></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp><relationalOp displayName="&lt;= 1 days Starts After Start Of" operatorType="Less Than or Equal To" quantity="1" type="SAS" unit="days"><logicalOp displayName="OR" type="or"><elementRef displayName="Anti-Hypertensive Pharmacologic Therapy : Medication, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5669" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="Laboratory Tests for Hypertension : Laboratory Test, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566a" type="qdm"/><elementRef displayName="ECG 12 lead or study order : Diagnostic Study, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5649" type="qdm"/></logicalOp><elementRef displayName="Occurrence A of BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New : Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" type="qdm"/></relationalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp></logicalOp></clause></group></measureGrouping><elementLookUp><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="attribute" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5648" name="Finding of Hypertension" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.2395" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5648" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Diagnostic Study, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5649" name="ECG 12 lead or study order" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.2448" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5649" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="National Quality Forum" datatype="Timing Element" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564c" name="Measurement Period" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.67.1.101.1.53" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="NQF" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564c" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Diagnosis, Active" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564d" name="Diagnosis of hypertension grouped" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.263" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564d" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement(R) (AMA-PCPI)" datatype="Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" name="Systolic Blood Pressure" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.526.3.1032" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d564f" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement(R) (AMA-PCPI)" datatype="Physical Exam, Finding" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" name="Diastolic Blood Pressure" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.526.3.1033" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8d5650" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement(R) (AMA-PCPI)" datatype="Physical Exam, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8e5656" name="Diastolic Blood Pressure" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.526.3.1033" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8e5656" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="American Medical Association-convened Physician Consortium for Performance Improvement(R) (AMA-PCPI)" datatype="Physical Exam, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8e5657" name="Systolic Blood Pressure" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.526.3.1032" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8e5657" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="attribute" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5666" name="Patient Reason refused" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.791" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5666" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Medication, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5669" name="Anti-Hypertensive Pharmacologic Therapy" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1476" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="RxNorm" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5669" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Laboratory Test, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566a" name="Laboratory Tests for Hypertension" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1482" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566a" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566c" name="Referral to Alternative Provider / Primary Care Provider" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1475" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566c" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566d" name="Followup within one year" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1474" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566d" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566e" name="Lifestyle Recommendation" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1508" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566e" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566f" name="Weight Reduction Recommended" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1510" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f566f" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5670" name="Dietary Recommendations" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1515" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5670" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5671" name="Physical Activity Recommendation" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1518" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5671" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5672" name="Moderation of ETOH Consumption Recommendation" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.823" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5672" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Encounter, Performed" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" instance="Occurrence A" name="BP Screening Denominator Encounter Codes Grouped New" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1920" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="Grouping" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5676" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="Intervention, Order" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5677" name="Followup within 4 weeks" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1537" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc8f5677" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="Quality Insights of Pennsylvania" datatype="attribute" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567c" name="Medical reason" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.600.1521" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="SNOMED-CT" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567c" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="National Library of Medicine" datatype="Patient Characteristic Sex" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567d" name="ONC Administrative Sex" oid="2.16.840.1.113762.1.4.1" suppDataElement="true" taxonomy="Administrative Sex" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567d" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="CDC NCHS" datatype="Patient Characteristic Race" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567e" name="Race" oid="2.16.840.1.114222.4.11.836" suppDataElement="true" taxonomy="CDC" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567e" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="CDC NCHS" datatype="Patient Characteristic Ethnicity" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567f" name="Ethnicity" oid="2.16.840.1.114222.4.11.837" suppDataElement="true" taxonomy="CDC" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc90567f" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="PHDSC" datatype="Patient Characteristic Payer" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc905680" name="Payer" oid="2.16.840.1.114222.4.11.3591" suppDataElement="true" taxonomy="Source of Payment Typology" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc905680" version="1"/><qdm codeSystemName="National Quality Forum" datatype="Patient Characteristic Birthdate" id="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc905681" name="birth date" oid="2.16.840.1.113883.3.560.100.4" suppDataElement="false" taxonomy="LOINC" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af14fc905681" version="1"/></elementLookUp><strata displayName="Stratification"><clause displayName="Stratum 1" type="stratum" uuid="40280381-3e93-d1af-013e-af1580555746"><logicalOp displayName="AND" type="and"/></clause></strata></measure>
